Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 74.
And this exercise, we are going to implement stack data structure and Java.
So first of all, open the A.J. idea or your I.D. Java ID this that we have created before link at least
double in closed circle link at last.
I will create a new Java class concerned about stack called Stack.
So this is a public class stack will serve as our main method of creating the stack.
So I told you that we have two methods of creating a stack, using a link at list or using an array.
Personally, I prefer using arrays.
OK.
I prefer working with arrays in the stack.
I will create an input array here and a private.
We need a and called top to indicate set up element, and we need to create and get capacity in order
to create the array with a specific capacity.
OK.
Again, I need from you to revise that stack stack, of course, and and lessons and I need from you
also to make and write these notes on paper and your notebook, because these are very important and
you revised them when you have an exam or an interview.
So that constructor creating a stack whenever you create an object from this stack class, you need
a constructor called Stack.
This is Stack took into 30 meter size and here are equal to new.
New and array of the same size.
OK, so whenever you create a stack, you specify its size and this size would be referring as an ashtray.
And we will create the new array with the same size.
So basically, we are creating an array and capacity equal to size.
And initially we have to initialized up to minus one goes and empty stack.
So this is how we initialize a stack and recreate a stack glass inside job.
Now let's add new methods to it.
We have the push, we have the part and we have is empty pop at the peak.
And so OK.
So these are the methods.
And let me mark this
method of exercise.
Exercise number 74.
OK?
Public.
We start by adding These are the methods.
One adding elements into stack.
So public void.
Bush, we have bush and we need to get the elements that we need to push, which is X.
OK.
So I need when I have to call Bush, I need to pass and enter an inner variable called X.
And this X would be clarifying that we need to check if it is full or not.
So I will call method called is it is full, is full.
And later on, I will create that then system that out that Brent and.
Stack is full of tech and system the exit one status one.
OK.
Otherwise, it will create a system that that brand alarm inserting.
And we put X here, and we insert it by making every act.
You see guys plus plus.
We increased the up.
This is the pretty increment, the top.
And we put array at this index equal to X.
We have seen this in the lecture in written in C language.
I learned you and teach you in this course how to think, how you get that knowledge, how you get the
concept behind pushing a popping and dealing with data structures, not learning you that syntax.
But by the way, I prefer writing everything in Java and C because we have the same concept that we
have.
We have the same algorithm and they are very similar.
See, and Jeff?
OK.
So what do you prefer?
I I can make new courses and you videos, so comment here in below the outcome of your favorite language.
OK?
In order to make new videos and new courses with it's like the language that you prefer.
OK, so the second method that we are going to implement in our stack is called removing the element
from the stack if there's like chopping.
So you remember popping so public and pop element.
So whenever we call this method pop, we will check if this stack is empty.
So I need to create a new method called empty, OK, system dot out dot print l
stack as empty.
So you are not emptying anything system that exit
one state this one.
Otherwise, it will return array at index top minus minus.
OK.
So we both increment and decrement the top and we specify return in the array.
As this index of is, this will be returning the element that we have removed.
OK.
OK, now let's check and create this is empty and is full method.
Three is empty,
so public is empty.
It's its answer is by true or false?
So it would be Boolean is.
A. It was return stub, as you would check, if the tarp equal equal to minus one, if it is true,
then it will return true.
Otherwise, it will return false.
It's a very simple method.
And again, we are going to check if it is full public.
Boolean is full and here return to equal equal to capacity minus one.
We check if to equal the capacity minus one.
If it returns true, it will go and here returning true.
Otherwise, it will return false.
Now let's make the fifth method called size the check, the return, the size of the stack size of stack.
So public event because we are searching for the size of add the stack size.
It will return the tarp because the tarp will indicate for us its position and the plus one because
the top the first element at the top is equal to zero.
So if we insert one element in the stack, the tarp will indicate it as zero.
We increase it by one, we add plus one here, so the tarp becomes one and indicate that there is a
one.
And OK.
It's very important to understand how to deal with data structures.
Method number six is the print stack.
So printing
stack, public void print stack.
This will make for us a method that will print our full stack.
But printing the stack the whole stack will assure for us or will use the loop.
Yes, you are thinking about that.
So we have used this in the previous data structure.
So and are equal to zero I less than
or equal to top and a plus plus this will indicate the system.
And this will print system that out that print and the array at the position.
OK.
It's very simple.
Now let's create in the main method and the try to check our product.
OK.
So here the driver, the main method.
The driver.
Public static void main.
And there's string parks.
Let's test our stack by creating a stack stack equal to new stack of five elements I need to make.
Five elements here I need to push you see guys, how I can push the elements.
One stack the push element to stack the push element.
Three.
Stack the push element four.
OK.
Now I need.
To top the atom.
But first of all, let me stand.
Let me print print stack.
OK.
Now, let's pop system that out.
Dr. Brent Allen.
Stack after popping.
Stack the top, OK, then stack the current stack.
Let's run, Nancy.
If is full here is full, it's on again.
And here we go.
Oh, so we have we need to.
And if the configuration and run.
The stack.
I need to run this tank and here.
Let me check.
Or is there or?
Sometimes it it may.
OK, there we go.
We have that configuration of running the previously created methods into the class.
So here we go.
We have.
Inserting one, inserting two, inserting three and setting forward if we are printing the list of the
stack one, two, three and four.
So it's very good.
After popping the last element, so stack after popping one, two or three, we have removed four from
our list.
OK, so we have removed this that the element using the pop from the stack.
OK, next videos we are will continue dealing with that stack with more.